<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Embedded Linux | ./gficht/]]></title>
  <link href="http://gficht.github.io/blog/categories/embedded-linux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gficht.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-25T23:12:58+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://gficht.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gficht]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Biped Robot]]></title>
    <link href="http://gficht.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/first-biped-robot/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-25T22:23:39+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://gficht.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/first-biped-robot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;d like to start off with the first robot I&#39;ve ever built. This was way back in 2008.</p>

<!--more-->

<p><img src="http://gficht.github.io/images/2015/04/1.jpg" alt="Biped" style="width: 200px;" align="left"/> I&#39;ve just started studying Automation and Robotics at Gdansk university of Technology. I decided to study that, after seeing a video of a robot called OmniZero.2 while still in high school. In the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a5O6ik1Jr6E">video</a> - the robot created by Mr Takeshi Maeda was moving with such agility it was unbelievable for me. He clearly left all the competitors behind. For a technical high school student learning electronics, this was a huge feat. So I decided to give it a go and build something similar. The efforts can be seen on the left.</p>

<p><img src="http://gficht.github.io/images/2015/04/2.jpg" alt="Controller" style="width: 200px;" align="right"/>It used 14 TowerPro SG-5010 servos, the frame was cut out of plexiglass. The design was completely in my head - I drew the parts that were supposed to be cut out in vector graphics. The servocontroller I also did by myself. The PCB was big and bulky. The ATmega16 was just enough to run 24 servos with the use of interrupts. Everything was so unprofessional - but it worked and made me feel good about it. After trying some simple control schemes(a simple walking gait) I abandoned the robot and sold the servos. I learned a lot of valuable things by doing the project. This prepared me for another one I&#39;d be doing in the future.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
